Miguel Ramos

Full Stack Developer

Vancouver, WA

360-980-0308 | drexelramos@gmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

OBJECTIVE

Self-motivated and accomplished business professional with over 10 years of experience within sales and financial services industry. Helped develop ecommerce website for cannabis company which processes over \$1.2M in sales annually. Looking to leverage extensive background in sales, effective communication and problem-solving into a new career as a Full Stack Developer.

SKILLS

Front End	Back End	Additional Tools/Skills	Professional Skills
HTML5 CSS3 jQuery JavaScript ES6 React React Hooks JSX	Node.js MongoDB PostgreSQL Express	Git GitHub Postman Enzyme RESTful APIs	Collaboration Creativity Critical Thinking Problem Solver Effective Communication

PROJECTS

Heavenly Buds | Live Site Link

- Collaborated to create ordering website for cannabis company increasing sales 140%
- Conceptualized custom design to reflect company branding and image
- Developed wireframes for improved UI/UX and logical website navigation. Coding done by freelancer
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | WordPress

Stocks Analysis | Project Link | GitHub

- Thinkful API project
- Designed & created application to retrieve a company's financial & stock information from multiple APIs
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | RESTful APIs

Omnifood | Project Link | GitHub

- Udemy project
- SPA for food delivery company utilizing JavaScript and CSS techniques
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Freelance | Vancouver, WA (remote)

January 2021 - Present

- Develop UI/UX strategies including wireframes and mockups for small businesses
- Design & create websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Co-Founder, Partner & Former VP of Sales

Heavenly Buds

January 2014 - Present

- 1 of 3 original Co-Founders of Heavenly Buds, licensed WA recreational cannabis producer/processor
- VP of Sales for 6 years, grew retail customer base to over 70 locations state-wide and revenue to over \$1.5M
- Helped design and create company product ordering website which allowed the business to reach full scalability

Account Manager

American Fidelity | Portland, OR (remote)

- September 2019 Present
- Achieved multiple insurance & investment licenses Life, Health, Series 63, Series 6
- Analyze financial and personal data to create customized health and retirement plans
- Tested multiple applications to develop contingency processes during COVID-19 pandemic contributing to the highest sales performance ever by the region

Territory Sales Manager

Kornerstone Credit | Seattle, WA (remote)

August 2018 - September 2019

- Helped grow this startup company from \$0 to over \$6 million in monthly company funding
- Successfully grew regional merchant partner base from 0 to over 120 locations
- Executed user testing on lending application to simplify transaction processing and increase loan approval rates

Property Manager

CM3 Real Estate | Vancouver, WA (remote)

May 2017 - November 2018

- Developed ecommerce site for selling real estate which decreased days on market by 50%
- Created SPA for purchasing real estate and implemented processes for automating the screening procedure of sellers increasing efficiency and scalability and decreasing phone time by 8 hours per week
- Negotiated, purchased and sold real estate in multiple states
- Created videos and digital marketing campaigns across many social media platforms and industry channels

Territory Sales Executive

Western Union | Seattle, WA (remote)

September 2005 - May 2017

- Received multiple awards for exceptional Teamwork and Sales results President's Club, Achiever Award, Driven Award, MVP Award
- Conducted user testing on money transfer desktop and mobile applications resulting in better UX, increased revenue and 15% higher app utilization within existing customers
- Trained 12 new employees on sales techniques, Compliance and Anti-Money Laundering policies and procedures
- Achieved profit increases ranging from 5% 18% per customer through renegotiation of money transfer contracts

EDUCATION

B.A. in Computer Science & Information Sciences

Drexel University

Minored: Business & Mathematics

Software Engineering

Thinkful

• Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on full stack mobile-first applications, algorithms and data structures